Contact

roque.anthony.velasco@gmail

www.linkedin.com/in/roqueanthony-velasco-b7802b76 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

HIPAA

Critical Thinking

Public Health

Languages

English

Filipino

Certifications

Registered Nurse

Public Health Nurse

HIV Specialist (AAHIVS)

Adult-Gerontology Primary Care Nurse Practitioner - Board Certified (AGPCNP-BC)

Certified Medical Surgical Registered Nurse (CMSRN)

Honors-Awards

Graduate Student Award for Excellence in Clinical Practice

Emma Lora Johnson Memorial Scholarship

Academy of Medical-Surgical Nurses Career Mobility Scholarship

Dorothea Lambert Memorial Scholarship

George & Ruth A. Warwick Scholarship in Nursing

Publications

Improving care of the patient receiving chemotherapy and biotherapy by a non-chemotherapy provider nurse

Roque Anthony Velasco

MS, APRN, AGPCNP-BC, CNS, CMSRN, ACRN, AAHIVS Palm Springs, California

Summary

Anthony Velasco is a Nurse Practitioner, credentialed HIV Specialist, and has been working in HIV care since 2010. He provides compassionate care to people living with and without HIV. He also performs high-resolution anoscopy for the detection and treatment of anal dysplasia. An ally of the trans community, he provides comprehensive gender-affirming care and advocates in creating better access to safe and gender-affirming spaces for all.

Prior to joining the Desert AIDS Project, he served as a clinical nurse supervisor at UC San Diego Health. He was awarded Excellence in Clinical Practice, was honored with the American Academy of Medical-Surgical Nurses Career Mobility Award, named by SD Voyager Magazine as one of San Diego's rising stars in 2019, was awarded 2019 Stonewall Humanitarian Award, and received the Association of Nurses in AIDS Care's Award for Excellence in Clinical Practice in HIV.

In addition to being a board-certified Nurse Practitioner and credentialed HIV Specialist, he also received certification in high-resolution anoscopy and board certification in medical-surgical nursing and AIDS nursing. He serves as a sub-investigator for HPV- and anal dysplasia-focused clinical studies funded by the National Institutes of Health, and research studies focusing on health disparities faced by the trans community in the Inland Empire.

He belongs to the World Professional Association for Transgender Health and the American Academy of Nurse Practitioners. He currently serves in the Nurse Practitioner Committee of the American Academy of HIV Medicine, president-elect of the Association of Nurses in AIDS Care Greater Palm Springs Chapter, and co-Chair of Desert AIDS Project's Transgender Wellness Program.

In each of his professional endeavors, he derives the greatest joy from building collaborative relationships with his patients, and from partnering with all members of the interdisciplinary team to offer caring, comprehensive, and compassionate care.

Experience

Desert AIDS Project Nurse Practitioner September 2016 - Present (3 years 10 months) Palm Springs, CA

- Manage comprehensive primary and specialized care of patients living with and without HIV infection of various ages, cultures, sexual orientations, and gender identities in a Federally Qualified Health Center.
- Perform high-resolution anoscopy and biopsy for detection, treatment, and management of anal dysplasia and lesions among high-risk individuals.
- Provide consultation for gender affirming hormone therapy as well as provide comprehensive primary and specialized care of transgender and gender non-conforming (TGNC) individuals.
- Provide consultation for pre-exposure prophylaxis (PrEP) and post-exposure prophylaxis (PEP); prescribe and monitor patients' PrEP and PEP regimens; and screen and treat STIs per CDC recommendations.
- Serve as a Subclinical Investigator for National Institute of Health Study on high-grade anal dysplasia among high-risk population.
- Train and precept nurse practitioner students and medical residents.
- Performs interdependent role as an expert resource in the area of HIV-care management and the screening, diagnosis, and treatment of anal dysplasia due to HPVs.
- Possesses and maintains advanced academic specialization as a nurse practitioner and didactic preparation and clinical expertise implementing appropriate "standardized procedures" (SP) related to HIV care and screening, diagnosis, and treatment of anal dysplasia.
- Provide and coordinate the healthcare, especially related to HIV infection, for adolescent and adult patients, provide patient/family education, promote safe continuity of care, perform specialized examinations with certification.

UCLA Health
Nurse Practitioner III
April 2018 - Present (2 years 3 months)
Los Angeles, California

- Performs specialized care of research subjects enrolled in Institutional Review Board (IRB) approved research protocols.

- Performs health assessments for research subjects including baseline and ongoing health history, routine research procedures, and routine and urgent care related to prescribed treatments and follow-up assessments.
- Performs interdependent role as an expert resource in the area of HIV-care management and the screening, diagnosis, and treatment of anal dysplasia due to HPVs.
- Possesses and maintains advanced academic specialization as a nurse practitioner and didactic preparation and clinical expertise implementing appropriate "standardized procedures" (SP) related to HIV care and screening, diagnosis, and treatment of anal dysplasia.
- Modifies treatment regimen after observing signs and symptoms of illness, reactions to treatment, general behavior and physical condition, and determines if they are abnormal findings consistent with the California Nurse Practice Act (Section 2725.b) and the IRB approved study protocol.
- Provide and coordinate the healthcare, especially related to HIV infection, for adolescent and adult patients, provide patient/family education, promote safe continuity of care, perform specialized examinations with certification.
- Participates in interdisciplinary and clinical rounds, the execution of research, provide education and support as well as make appropriate referrals.
- Maintains specialized knowledge: diagnosis, management, patient education and treatment (therapies) of HPV-related neoplasia, especially related to genital disease.

Walden University Clinical Nurse Instructor (Honorary)

August 2019 - February 2020 (7 months)

- Honorary Clinical Nurse Instructor status with Walden University.
- Clinical Instruction to Adult-Gerontology Primary Care Nurse Practitioner students for PRAC 6531: Advanced Practice Care of Adults Across the Lifespan and NRNP/PRAC 6540: Advanced Practice Care of Frail Elders
- Lead discussions and elicit information from students which demonstrate that students are learning and accomplishing the clinical objectives.
- Provide and coordinate clinical teaching activities in the clinical setting to include student assignments and clinical supervision.
- Maintain clinical standards and course expectations throughout each course or term.
- Evaluate student performance. Meets with students at midterm for formal evaluation and again

at the end of the course as to progress and performance.

- Maintain the professional practice knowledge base needed to instruct learners in contemporary nursing practice.

UC San Diego Health
Clinical Nurse Supervisor
December 2010 - September 2016 (5 years 10 months)
San Diego, California

- Multiple promotions from acute care clinician to micro-system leader within a Magnet- recognized academic medical institution (Clinical Nurse II promotion in 07/2010, Clinical Nurse III promotion in 07/2013, and Clinical Nurse II-Supervisor in 11/2014).
- Assist in managing overall operations of a busy 22-bed acute medicine unit that specializes in infectious diseases, HIV, and opportunistic infections and malignancies with 5,784 patient days, 34.1 FTEs, and 40 licensed staff and ancillary personnel.

Key Accomplishments: Spearheaded successful implementation of unit- and division-based quality projects, which resulted in a decrease in chemotherapy-related quality variance report by 80%, increased certified chemotherapy provider nurses by 280%, standardization of chemotherapy handoff hospital-wide, and overall improvement of chemotherapy-related knowledge and skills of both chemotherapy provider and non-chemotherapy provider nurses and staff in the medical-surgical division. Served as chairman of the unit's quality and practice council, represented the unit in various hospital-wide councils (Share Governance Nursing Cabinet, Image of Nursing and Magnet Committee, Professional Development Council, and Nursing Research and EBP Council), and assisted the Department of Nursing Education Development and Research in electronic medical record training of nursing students and new employees.

Education

University of Colorado Anschutz Medical Campus

Doctor of Philosophy - PhD, Nursing (Health Care Systems Research

Focus) · (2020 - 2023)

San Diego State University-California State University Master of Science (M.S.), Nurse Practitioner and Clinical Nurse Specialist · (2013 - 2016)

San Diego State University-California State University
Bachelor of Science in Nursing, Minor in Personality and Social
Psychology · (2007 - 2009)

Southwestern Community College District Associate in Arts, Transfer Studies · (2005 - 2007)